## **ARULMARY**

# Senior Quality Engineer

#### **Summary**

Having over all 9+ years of extensive experience in IT Industry as Quality Engineer and Business Analysts. Specialized experience in Functional QA, Customer interactions, Implementation of UAT Process. Requirement gathering and Product support for Lorenzo Clinicals at Aachen General Hospital, Germany.

## **Experience Includes:**

- Hands on experience in working Waterfall and Agile SDLC methodologies
- Hands on experience in handling multiple teams/projects
- Proven ability to manage teams and resources
- Proven ability to mentor and train resources
- Test Plan Creation / Tracking / Updating
- Client Facing Skills / Lead Meetings
- Requirement analysis and gathering
- Creating Test Plan
- Test Case Creation / Execution / Defect Management
- Manual and Automation testing
- Expertise in Test Management Tool
- Mentored team members on Agile concepts
- Monitored & Tracking Agile specific metrics, SLA's and KPI's and Implemented productivity improvements

#### **Professional Experience**

## **Business Analyst Consultant** @ servwing

#### Thinkinfinity Technology. Sep 2018 to March 2022

Requirement Gathering and creating BRD. Talent Acquisition.

## Software Test Engineer Teledata Info., Pvt Ltd., Feb 2003 to Oct 2005

Creating Test Cases using User Requirements. Performing Peer review on Test Cases.

Formulated test scenarios using a variety of testing techniques (integration, system, black box, regression, boundary, etc).

Tracking test coverage and test progress.

Tracking defects on an in-house **Defect Management Tool**. Executed test scripts in QTP.

## Senior Quality Engineer iSOFT R&D Private Ltd Nov 2005 to June 2009

Managed and guided a team of 4 members

Gathering Requirement from Client

Creating Master Test documents and Test Plan Allocate and track the assigned task to the team Conduct

triage meetings with Business and QA team

Mentoring the team to understand business process and testing strategies

Reviewed SIT Test Cases, Regression test cases and End to End Testing

Managed testing process and review QA artifacts and ensure the test coverage

Monitored Test Execution status and Defect Tracking in Telelogic Tool

Reviewing Functional Business flow test case & Business logic

Planned and executed risk based testing Circulate MOM, and Action Items

Report Prepared: Defect status report and Build weekly status report

### **Academic Qualification**

**Bachelor of Science (Computer Science) 1999-2002** 

(University of Madras).

Master of Computer Application – (IGNOU). Diploma in Advance Software Technology.

Brain bench Certification in Software Testing.

#### **Personal Information**

**Phone:** +91 9360188066

Reach: arulmary.710@gmail.com

Skills: Quality Assurance, Pre-Sales & Business Analyst

**Software**: SQL